A Guide to the H. Franklin Minor Papers, 1969-2004
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
H. Franklin Minor Papers, 1969-2004
The Library of Virginia
43442
1.8 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The item in Box 1, Folder 5 is closed until 2039 due to privacy concerns.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marian T. Minor, Richmond.
Biographical Information
Henry Franklin Minor was born in Richmond, Virginia on 1 May 1933. He was the son of Philip H. Minor (1900-1984) and Mary Lynn Upshaw (b. 1900). Minor earned a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry from the University of Richmond (1956) and the degree of Juris Doctor from the T. C. Williams Law School (1959). He practiced law and was a real estate broker, and also served on the board of directors of United Dominion Realty Trust. Minor was also a master tree farmer and avid naturalist. He served on the board of directors of the Friends of the Virginia State Archives and the King and Queen County Historical Society. Minor married Joyce Sisson on 16 March 1963. He died in Richmond on 22 December 2006, and is buried in Forest Lawn Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1968-2004, of H. Franklin Minor (1933-2006) of Richmond, Virginia, including historical and genealogical research on the Arnold, Baylor, Broaddus, Flood, Harrison, McCall, Minor, Temple, and Upshaw families of Caroline, Essex, King and Queen, and King William Counties, Virginia. Much of the material was used in preparation for articles Minor wrote for the Magazine of Virginia Genealogy and Tidewater Virginia Families. There are copies and transcriptions of deeds, land patents, plats, tax records, and published sources, as well as correspondence and drafts of Minor's articles. There are also genealogical notes compiled by Mary Lynn (Upshaw) Minor (b. 1900).
Contents List
- Bagby, Travis. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Baylor vs. Harrison. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bills of Exchange - Archibald McCall and William Lee. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Broaddus. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Broaddus, Woodford B. and Jean D. - Wills. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  This material is closed until 2039 due to privacy concerns.
- "Clydeside" - Joseph Ewing Article in Virginia Magazine. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Clydeside" - George Clayton Deeds/Robert Hunter Diary. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Clydeside" - McCall Letters, Land and Personal Property Taxes. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Clydside" - Wills - Flood/McCall. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Col. John Martin of Caroline and John Martin, Junior, His Nephew" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Course of Descent. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "A Day in Court" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Descendants of John Minor" - Compiled by W. Avery Miner, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- District Court Receipts. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Dunn, William (B.). (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "The First Arbitrator, John Robinson, 1683-1749 - Bond, Essex County, July 10, 1738" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Freshwater, Barbara (St. John). (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Green, George and Eldred - Wills. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Harrison. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Harrison - Pre-1700. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Harrison - 1710's. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Harrison - 1720's. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Harrison - 1730's. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Harrison - 1740's. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Harrison - 1750's. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Harrison - 1760's. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Harrison - 1770's. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Harrison - 1780's. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Harrison - 1800's. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Andrew Harrison (Orange County, NC). (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Andrew Harrison (1712 Ejectment). (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Andrew Harrison, fl. 1743, King and Queen County" by H. Franklin Hall. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Harrison, Andrew - Deeds, 1750-1769. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Harrison, Andrew (Sonds of the Revolution). (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Harrison, Andrew (Robert M. Torrence). (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Harrison, Charles P. (b. 1797). (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Harrison, Martha Boulware. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Harrison, Mary T. - Letter to Robert Harrison, 1842. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Harrison, Spencer. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- "Harrison vs. Baylor" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Harrison Wheel (Temple). (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Hook, Harriett B. - Skinker Family. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Jaell Harrison" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
- Jerdone, Francis. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Jerdone Letterbook. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Jerdone Letterbook (Dr. Edgar MacDonald). (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "The Legacy of Anthony Arnold: He Had No Kindness for Kings" by H. Franklin Minor. (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
- Lidderdale. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mill - 502 Acres - McCall. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Motley. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "New Glasgow". (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Page, William - Land Tax. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Patterson Plat. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Pierce, Marjorie Boswell. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Plats. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "Providence" - Deed. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ring's Quarter. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Robinson, John - List of Debtors. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Scottish Records - William Cunningham and Company, Fort Pitt. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Smith, Shirley (re: Davis). (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Story, Joshua - Patents. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Tax Records - Caroline County, 1782-1814. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Tax Records - Caroline County - Upshaw/Harrison. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Toombs. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Upshaw. (Box 4, Folder 5-9)
- Upshaw, Edwin - "Mount Clement". (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Upshaw Family Journal. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Upshaw-Harrison. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Upshaw, Jack. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Upshaw, James. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Upshaw, James Harrison. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- White - John, Ambrose, William, Chilion. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Will of Ann (Arnold) Temple. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Waring, John Upshaw. (Box 4, Folder 18)